Guide to the Yale University Divinity School Memorabilia Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Audio-Visual Materials, Series V; *NOTE: CDs of Convocation lectures are available for purchase from the Yale Divinity School Bookstore (http://www.yaledivinitybookstore.com/category/audio-and-lectures)
  - Audio
    - Named Lectures
      - Cheney Lectures
        - Stendahl, Krister: "Spiritual Questions to Theol. Distinctions" (2 Tapes), 1991 (Box 61)
        - Ulanov, Ann B: "Destructiveness and the Spiritual Life" (Tape), 1995 (Box 61)
        - Childs, Brevard: "Interpreting the Bible in the Midst of Cultural Change" (Tape), 1996 (Box 61)
        - Platten, Stephen: "Lambeth 1998: Can Anglicanism Survive?" (Tape) (Box 61)
        - Matthews, Victoria: "Theological Education" (Tape), 2000 (Box 61)
        - Coakley, Sarah: "The Woman at the Altar: Cosmological Disturbance or Gender Subversion" (on order), 2002 (Box 61)
        - McIntosh, Mark: "How God Makes Theologians" (CD), 2004 (Box 61)
        - L'Engle, Madeleine: "Separation of the Stars" (CD/Tape), n.d. (Box 61)
        - Schwartz, Regina: "Towards a Sacramental Poetics", 2006 (Box 61)
      - Chisholm Lectures
        - Newsom, Carol: "Angelic and Human Desire and the Origin of Evil: 1 Enoch 6-16" (Tape), 2000 (Box 62)
      - Ensign Lectures
        - May, William F: "Money and the Professions: Medicine, Law, and the Ministry" (on order), 1995
        - Oduyoye, Mercy Amba: "Religious Issues in the Creative Writings of West African Women" (Tape), 1996 (Box 62)
        - Prejean, Sr. Helen, CSJ: "Dead Man Walking - The Journey" (Tape), 1997 (Box 62)
        - Elshtain, Jean Bethke: "The Sin of Pride and the Triumph of Economics" (Tape), 1998 (Box 62)
        - Williams, Dolores S: "Is Liberation Enough: Beyond the Temple Door There Is No Promised Land", 1999 (Box 62)
        - Fortune, Marie: "This is Not About You: The Challenge of Ministry and Boundaries" (Tape), 2000 (Box 62)
        - Farley, Margaret A. and Thomas P. Duffy: "Death, Dying, and Clinical Practice" Ensign/Sorenson Lecture (2 Tapes), 2001 (Box 62)
        - Ammerman, Nancy: "Tabernacles in the Wilderness: Forming Communities of Faith in a Diverse and Changing World" (Tape), 2003 (Box 62)
        - Dulles, Cardinal Avery (Tape), 2003 (Box 62)
        - Cupitt, Don, 2005 (Box 62)
      - Haskins Lectures
        - Russell, Val and Letty Russell: "Sexism in Religious Language" (CD/Tape), 1976 (Box 62)
        - Smith, Alfred J: "Ministry For the 21st Century: A Tale Between Two Cities" (Tape), 1991-1992 (Box 62)
      - Kavanagh Lectures
        - Baldovin, John F., S.J: "Low the Full Final Sacrifice: On the Seriousness of Christian Liturgy"(Tape), 2001 (Box 62)
        - Bradshaw, Paul F: "Liturgy in the Absence of Hippolytus" (on order), 2002
        - Mitchell, Nathan D.: "From Text to Tablature: Reimaging Litugical Language Today" (CD), 2007 (Box 62)
      - Kingsbury Lectures
        - Peale, Norman Vincent (Audio Reel), 1960 (Box 63)
        - Corrigan, Rt. Rev. D. (2 Audio Reels), 1967 (Box 63)
        - Meyers, Bishop of California (Audio Reel), 1967 (Box 63)
        - Gustafson, James M: "Ethics and Experimentation:A procedural Proposal" (Audio Reel), 1969 (Box 63)
        - Moore, Bishop (Audio Reel), n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kittel Lectures
        - Levenson, Jon D: "Exodus and Liberation" (2 CDs/Tape), 1989 (Box 64)
        - Harrelson, Walter: "Isaiah 35:1-10: Notes on the Use for Advent" (Tape), 1989 (Box 64)
        - Miuer, Rev. Patrick D: "Things Too Marvelous: Prayers Women Prayed" (Tape), 1990 (Box 64)
        - Newsom, Carol: "Language and Friendship in the Book of Job" (CD/Tape), 1991 (Box 64)
        - Niditch, Susan: "Oral Culture and Written Documents: Five Attitudes to Writing in the Hebrew Bible"(Tape), 1993-1994 (Box 64)
      - Mary Fitch Page Lectures
        - Fr. Burkshart: "Lecture" (Audio Reel), 1966 (Box 64)
        - Knox, John: "The Problem of Faith in teh Contemporary Church" (Tape), 1968 (Box 64)
        - Coburn, John B: "Theological Education in University Setting" (Tape), 1981 (Box 64)
      - Parks-King Lectures
        - Weems, Dr. Renita J: "After the Bush Stops Burning" (Tape), 1989 (Box 64)
        - Riggs, Marcia Y: "Ethics For Living a Dream Deferred" (Tape), 1990 (Box 64)
        - Butts, Dr. Calvin O: "An Apology for Blacks" (Tape), 1991 (Box 64)
        - Franklin, Robert, 2004 (Box 64)
        - Copeland, M. Shawn: "The Fierce Urgency of Now: Critical Black Theology and Hope", 2009 (Box 64)
      - Pitt Lectures
        - Ebeling, Gerhard: "The Heart of the Reformation" (Audio Reel/Tape), 1968 (Box 65)
        - Price, Charles P: " Works of the Spirit: The Role of the Spirit in the Eucharist and Baptism; The Way of the Spirit: Notes on a Dynamic Metaphysic" (Audio Reel), 1975 (Box 65)
        - Williams, Rowan: "Mission and Spirituality" (2 CDs/Tapes), 1991 (Box 65)
        - Dyer, Rt. Rev. Mark: "Lambeth and the Future of the Anglican Communion" (Tape), 1997 (Box 65)
        - Gray, Donald: "450 Years of teh Book of Common Prayer in the Parish" (Tape), 1999 (Box 65)
        - Spinks, Bryan D: "Berkeley, Liturgical Scholars and the Liturgical Movement" (Tape), 2001 (Box 65)
        - Tanner, Kathryn: "Incarnation and Atonement: A Feminist Reappraisal" (Tape), 2003 (Box 65)
        - Earnes, Robin: "Where Now for World Anglicanism?" (CD), 2005 (Box 65)
        - Williams, Jane: "Sin and Salvation" (CD), 2007 (Box 65)
        - Gray, Donald: "450 Years of teh Book of Common Prayer in the Parish" (Tape), n.d (Box 65)
        - Van Culin, Samuel "This Generous Gift" (Tape), n.d. (Box 65)
      - Shaffer Lectures
        - Weigle, Luther A: "The Translation of the Bible into English" (3 Tapes), 1953 (Box 66)
        - Cullman, Oscar: "The Anticipated Delivery of the Body According to the New Testament" (Tape), 1955 (Box 66)
        - von Rad, Gerhard: "Promise and Fulfillment in the Bible" (Tape), 1961 (Box 66)
        - Miller, Randolph: "Theology and the Laity" (Tape), 1969 (Box 66)
        - Minear, Paul: "Christ and the Prophetic Succession" (4 Tapes), 1974 (Box 66)
        - Meyer, Paul W: "The Justification of Jesus" (3 Tapes), 1976 (Box 66)
        - Brown, Raymond E: "The Importance of Jesus for the Johannine Community in its Last Hour" (4 Tapes), 1978 (Box 66)
        - Keck, Leander E: "Jesus in the New Testament--Matthew: Jesus and the Righteousness of Persons; Paul: Jesus and the Righteousness of God; John: Jesus' Right to Represent God" (3 Tapes), 1980 (Box 66)
        - Koester, Helmut: "Books of the Divine Man; From Wisdom Books to Gnostic Dialogue; From Passion to Narrative Biography" (3 Tapes), 1981 (Box 66)
        - Frei, Hans: "Interpretation and Jesus Christ" (3 Tapes), 1983 (Box 66)
        - Betz, Hans Dieter: "The Sermon on the Mount: The Challenge Continues" (3 Tapes), 1985 (Box 66)
        - de Jonge, Marinus: "The Nature of the Earliest Response to Jesus; Jesus' Mission and His Death on the Cross; Jesus as Inaugurator of God's Kingdom. Eschatology and Christology" (3 Tapes), 1989 (Box 67)
        - Sanders, Ed P: "Jesus: Religous Type and Cause of Death in Recent Interpretation; Jesus as Sage; Jesus as Eschatological Prophet" (3 CDs/Tapes), 1991 (Box 67)
        - Hengel, Martin: "The Historical Jesus: Methods and Sources; Galilean Prophet and Healer; The Crucifed Messiah" (3 Tapes), 1992 (Box 67)
        - Hooker, Morna D: "Mighty in Deed and Word" (3 Tapes), 1995 (Box 67)
        - Wright, N.T.: "The Resurrection of the Messiah" (3 Tapes), 1996 (Box 67)
        - Malberbe, Abraham: "Christology in Context: The Pastoral Epistles" (3 Tapes), 1998 (Box 67)
        - Martyn, Louis J: "Inviting Paul into the Current Theological Discussion" (3 Tapes), 2000 (Box 67)
        - Garrett, Susan: "No Ordinary Angel: Jesus and the Angels in the Bible and Today" (on order), 2002 (Box 67)
        - Ehrman, Bart D.: "Christ in the Early Christian Tradition: Texts Disputed and Apocrphal--Christ Come in the Flesh, Christ in the Divine Man, Christ Against the Jews" (CD), 2004 (Box 67)
        - Meier, John P.: "On the Danger of Making Jesus a Christian; The Test Case of Law and Morality: 1. The Jewish Jesus on Jewish Divorce. -- The Jewish Jesus and the Sabbath. -- 3. The Jewish Jesus and Purity Laws.", 2006 (Box 67)
      - Sorensen Lectures
        - Wolin, Sheldon: "Public Philosophy and Civil Religion" (2 CDs/Tapes), 1981 (Box 68)
        - Neal, Sr. M.A.: "Altruism as Public Virtue: Values and Interests" (Tape), 1983 (Box 68)
        - Hollenbach, Rev. David, S.J.: "Justice-as-Participation: A Christian Challenge to the U.S. Economy" (Tape), 1985 (Box 68)
        - Price, David: "Ethics and the Work of the Legislature" (CD/Tape), 1990 (Box 68)
        - McGovern, George: "The New World Order" (CD/Tape), 1991 (Box 68)
        - Gustafson, James M: "Making Theology Intelligible: An Interpretation of Richard Niebuhr" (Tape), 1995 (Box 68)
        - Childress, James: "Religion and Public Policy: The Controversy About Human Cloning" (Tape), 1997 (Box 68)
        - Hauerwas, Stanley: "Enduring" (Tape), 2000 (Box 68)
        - Farley, Margaret A. and Thomas P. Duffy: Ensign/Sorenson Lecture (2 Tapes), 2001 (Box 62)
        - Sider, Ronald: "Evaluating the Faith-Based Initiative: Is Charitable Choice Good Public Policy?" (on order), 2002
        - Curran, Charles E: "The Just War Theory Today: One Perspective" (Tape), 2003 (Box 68)
        - Mollica, Dr. Richard (CD), 2005 (Box 68)
        - Williams, Delores: "Is Liberation Enough: Beyond the Temple Door is No Promised Land" (Tape) (Box 68)
      - Taylor Lectures
        - Smith, Cantwell N: "Is the Koran the Word of God"(Audio Reel), 1963 (Box 69)
        - Outler, Albert: "The Hallowing of Life" (4 Tapes), 1975 (Box 69)
        - Pannenberg, Wolfhart: "Protestant Piety and Guild; Eucharistic Piety; Sanctification and Politics" (3 Tapes), 1977 (Box 69)
        - Ricoeur, Paul: "The Paradox of Time in Augustine and Heidegger; Narrataive and the Paradoxes of Time" (3 Tapes), 1979 (Box 69)
        - Hartt, Julian: "The One God and the Several Worlds" (Tape), 1982 (Box 69)
        - Mitchell, Basil: "Reason Restricted; Reason Restored; Reason Redeemed" (3 Tapes), 1986 (Box 69)
        - Solle: "On Work and Love" (3 Tapes), 1984 (Box 70)
        - Cobb, John: "The Impact of Secular Disciplines on Theology. Case Study: Cultural Anthropology" (3 Tapes), 1988 (Box 70)
        - Douglas, Jame Dempsey: "God's Working in History and 16th Century Witnesses: The Historican of Theology and Witness; The Vision of John Calvin; The Vision of Marie Dentiere and Antoine Fromment" (3 Tapes), 1990 (Box 70)
        - Wiles, M: "Christian Theology Dialogues: Precedents of the Past" (3 Tapes), 1992 (Box 70)
        - McFague, Sally: "Christianity and Postmodern Science" (3 Tapes), 1994 (Box 70)
        - Kaufman, Gordon D: "Christian Theology in Our Pluralistic World" (3 Tapes), 1995 (Box 70)
        - Moltmann, Jurgen: "What is Theology" (3 Tapes), 1997 (Box 70)
        - Tracy, David: "God: Incomprehensible or Hidden: Forms and Fragments of Theological Language; The Hidden God as Entry; The Incomprehensible God", 1999 (Box 70)
        - Martyn, J. Louis: "Inviting Paul into the Current Theological Discussion" (on order), 2000
        - Wolterstorff, Nicholas: "The Place of Religion in a Secular Society" (3 Tapes), 2001 (Box 71)
        - Kelsey, David: "Some Meanings of Redemption: What Earthly Difference Could Jesus Make Now?; The Fellow Sufferer; Broken Circles" (3 Tapes), 2003 (Box 71)
        - Thomas, Linda E.: "Theology and Anthropology from a Womanist Perspective--The Aesthetic Dimensions of Religion in South Africa" (CD), 2007 (Box 71)
      - Templeton Lectures
        - Barbour, Ian: "Science, Technology, and the Christian Tradition" (Tape), 1999 (Box 71)
      - Terry Lectures
        - Hans, Kung: "Freud and the Problem of God" (Box 72a 4 Tapes/4 Audio Reels/ Box 72b 6 CDs), 1978 (Box 72A–72B)
        - Jonas, Hans: "Technology, Utopia, and Ethics" (4 Tapes), 1980 (Box 71)
        - Hartman, Dr. David (3 Tapes), 1998 (Box 71)
      - Wright Lectures
        - Latourette, Kenneth Scott: "A Call to Mission and Unity" (Tape), 1953 (Box 71)
        - Hartshorne, Hugh: "Theological Education and the Churches" (Audio Reel), 1954 (Box 73)
    - YDS Faculty lectures
      - Ahlstrom, Sydney
        - Hospitality (2 tapes), n.d. (Box 73)
      - Ammerman, Nancy
        - American Religious Organizations, ca.1997-98 (Box 73)
      - Anderson, Bernard
        - "The Word of God in the Old Testament" (Tape), 1988 (Box 73)
      - Annand, James
        - "Homiletics" (Tape), 1987 (Box 73)
      - Bainton, Roland
        - "Lecture" (Audio Reel), 1951 (Box 73)
        - "Freedom's Religious Foundations" (Audio Reel), 1954 (Box 73)
        - "Lecture" (Audio Reel), 1957 (Box 73)
        - "Erasmus" (2 Tapes), 1968 (Box 73)
        - "Behold the Christ" (Tape), 1974 (Box 73)
        - "Birthday Address" (Tape), 1974 (Box 73)
        - "Polish Women in the Reformation"(Tape), 1974 (Box 73)
        - "Christians on War and Peace" (Tape), 1975 (Box 74)
        - "Social, Cultural, and Religious Change in Contemporary Poland" (Tape), 1976 (Box 74)
        - "Martin Luther's Christmas Sermon" (Tape), 1977 (Box 74)
        - "'New' War and Peace" (CD/Tape), 1980 (Box 74)
        - "Erasmus: Prophet of Peace in Church and State" (Tape), 1982 (Box 74)
        - "History of the Christian Family" (Tape), n.d. (Box 74)
        - "Impressions of Trip to Poland" (Tape) (Box 74)
        - "Luther's Bible Meditations" (Tape), n.d. (Box 74)
        - "Luther's Christmas Sermon/ Interview on the Importance of Erasmus Today" (Tape), n.d. (Box 74)
        - "Martin Luther and the Reformation" (Tape) (Box 74)
        - "The Story of YDS", n.d. (Box 74)
        - "Women of the Reformation", n.d. (Box 74)
      - Calhoun, Robert Lowry
        - "The Need for a New Liberal Theology" (Tape), n.d. (Box 75)
      - Childs, Brevard
        - "Old Testament Interpretation" (Tapes CD), 1982 (Box 75)
        - "The Rise and Fall of Biblical Theology" (Tape CD) (Box 75)
      - Cook, John W.
        - "Building Utopia: Visionary Architecture" (CD/Tape), n.d. (Box 75)
      - Crane, Henry H.
        - "The Evangelism of Emphasis" (Audio Reel) Filed with Neibuhr sermon: "Matt. 5:44", n.d. (Box 75)
      - Daly, Mary
        - "Sexual Caste System" (CD/Tape), n.d. (Box 75)
      - Dittes, James
        - "When Ministry Fails - Burnout or Recycle" (Tape), 1984 (Box 75)
      - Farley, Margaret
        - "Conversation" (CD/Tape), 1988 (Box 75)
        - "History of Christian Ethics" (box of taped class lectures), 1984 (Box 76)
        - "Sexual Justice: An Approach to a Contemporary Sexual Ethic" (Tape), 1988 (Box 75)
        - "Issues in the Ordination of Women" (CD/Tape) Joan Forsberg co-speaker, n.d. (Box 75)
      - Forsberg, Joan
        - "Issues in the Ordination of Women" (CD/Tape) Margaret Farley co-speaker, n.d. (Box 75)
      - Greer, Rowan
        - "Family in the Early Church" (Tape), 1979 (Box 77)
        - "Conversation on Pluralism in the Ancient Church and in Anglicanism" (CD/Tape), 1987 (Box 77)
      - Hawkins, Peter
        - Dante, 1997-98 (Box 107)
      - Hays, Richard
        - "Prayer in the New Testament" (Tape), 1986 (Box 77)
        - "Redaction Criticism, The Jesus Project and New Testament Ethics" (CD/Tape), 1987 (Box 77)
        - "Biblical Witness for Peacemaking" (Tape), n.d. (Box 77)
        - "Response to Carl F. H. Henry's Lecture: The Crisis of Biblical Authority" (Tape filed under Henry) (Box 77)
        - "Wesleyan Tradition and Biblical Exegesis" (Tape) co-speaker David Lull (Box 77)
      - Hicks, Lansing
        - "Old Testament Interpretation" (Tapes), 1983-1984 (Box 78)
        - "Conversations on Recent Developments in Old Testament Studies" (CD/Tape), n.d. (Box 77)
      - Holmer, Paul
        - "C.S. Lewis: History and Criticism" (Tape), 1974 Feb 5 (Box 63)
        - "C.S. Lewis on Morality" (2 CDs/Tape), 1974 Feb 12 (Box 63)
        - Thinking as a Christian: "Kierkegaard: Jesus Christ as Teacher; The Self Being a Subject; Thinking as a Christian for Self-Examination", 1978 (Box 63)
        - "Luther and Music", 1983 Nov 2 (Box 63)
        - "Opening Convocation Address", 1986 Sep 3 (Box 63)
        - "Kierkegaard: Aesthetics and Ethics" (Box 63)
        - Kierkegaard: Self as Subject, 1978 Apr 12 (Box 63)
        - Kierkegaard: For Self-Examination, 1978 April 26 (Box 63)
        - "The Scope of Kierkegaard's Literature", n.d. (Box 63)
      - Johnson, Luke Timothy
        - "New Testament Interpretations" (Sermons 1-70 on audiotape), 1980-1981 (Box 49–50)
      - Kavanaugh, Aidan
        - "On Liturgy" (2 CDs), n.d. (Box 77)
      - Keck, Leander
        - "Paul and the Jews" (Tape) (Box 63)
        - Installation as Dean of YDS, 1980 Feb 11 (Box 63)
      - Kelsey, David
        - "On Recent Trends in Theology" (Tape), 1987 (Box 77)
        - "Utopia: A Theological Critique" (CD/Tape) co-speaker Cornel West, n.d. (Box 83)
      - Kittel, Bonnie
        - "Old Testament Interpretation" (box of lecture tapes), 1981 (Box 79A)
        - "Old Testament Interpretation" (box of lecture tapes), 1982 (Box 79B)
      - Latourette, Kenneth Scott
        - "Lecture" (recorded on Niebuhr Audio Reel labled "Niebuhr"), n.d. (Box 101)
      - Lindbeck, George
        - "The Future of the Church in a de-Christianized Society" (Audio Reel), 1970 (Box 80)
        - "The Reformation Reassessed: Paul Tillich on the Reformation" (2 CDs/2 Tape), 1980 (Box 80)
        - "Liberating Words" (Tape), 1983 (Box 80)
        - "Christian Theology from Augustine to Luther" (3 Tapes), n.d. (Box 80)
        - "The Hartford Heresies" (2CDs/1 Tape), n.d. (Box 80)
        - "Lecture" (Tape) (Box 80)
      - Lovelace, Richard
        - "Homosexuality and the Church", 1984 Apr 9 (Box 80)
        - "Renewal in the Mainline Denomination", 1984 Apr 9 (Box 80)
      - Luccock, Halford E.
        - "Measurements" (Audio Reel), 1951 (Box 80)
        - "About Finding One's Self" (Audio Reel), 1954 (Box 80)
        - "We Have Found Him" (Audio Reel), 1956 (Box 80)
        - "The Power of the Amateur" (Audio Reel), 1957 (Box 80)
      - Lull, David
        - "Wesleyan Tradition and Biblical Exegesis" (Tape) co-speaker Richard Hays (Box 77)
      - Malherbe, Abraham
        - "New Testament Milieux" (4 Tapes), 1977 (Box 81)
        - "Family in the New Testament" (Tape), n.d. (Box 81)
        - "Toward a Theology of Aging: Biblical Perspectives" (Tape) co-speaker Robert Wilson, n.d. (Box 81)
      - Miller, Randolph Crump
        - "Process Theology" (3 Tape set), n.d. (Box 81)
        - "The Theology of Jazz" (Tape), n.d. (Box 81)
        - "Toward a Theology of Family", n.d. (Box 81)
      - Minear, Paul
        - "Fear or Faith" (Tape), 1984 (Box 81)
      - Muehl, William
        - "The Lone Ranger" (Audio Reel) Seminar on Christian Ministry, 1961 (Box 81)
        - "Baccalaureate Sermon" (Tape), 1976 (Box 81)
        - "Free Speech and the Crisis of Pluralism" (Tape), 1984 (Box 81)
      - Nouwen, Henri J.M.
        - "The Spiritual Life: A Christian Perspective" (CD/Tape) Spirituality Forum, 1981 (Box 82)
        - "The Family and The Christian Church" (Tape) Family Forum, 1990 (Box 82)
        - "Care" (CD/Tape), n.d. (Box 82)
        - "Celibacy" (CD/Tape) Sexuality Forum, n.d. (Box 82)
        - "Compassion and Vincent Van Gogh" (2 CD/ Tape set) (Box 82)
        - "Wounded Healer" (2 CD/3 Tape set) (Box 82)
        - "What is Prayer?" (2 CD/Tape set), n.d. (Box 82)
      - Ogletree, Thomas
        - "Escatology and Ethics", 1993-1994 (Box 83)
      - Outler, Albert
        - "Chapel Sermon" (Audio Reel), 1959 (Box 83)
      - Russell, Letty
        - "Family as Partnership" (Tape), n.d. (Box 83)
      - Canon, Russell, Martin
        - "Feminist Theology: Third World Perspective" (Box of Tapes), 1987 (Box 84)
      - Stroup, John
        - "Luther and Worship" (Tape) (Box 83)
      - West, Cornel
        - "Philosophy Class Lecture" (3 Tapes), 1985 (Box 83)
        - "Utopia: A Theological Critique" (CD/Tape) co-speaker David Kelsey, n.d. (Box 83)
      - Williams, Colin
        - "Barmen - Interview" (Tape), n.d. (Box 83)
        - "Jerusalem: City of Peace or Conflict" (Tape), n.d. (Box 83)
      - Wilson, Robert
        - "Old Testament Interpretation" (box of lecture tapes), 1981-1982 (Box 85A)
        - "Old Testament Interpretation" (box of lecture tapes), 1983-1984 (Box 85B)
        - "Old Testament Interpretation" (box of lecture tapes), n.d. (Box 85C)
        - "Apocalyptic: Ancient and Modern" (Tape) (Box 83)
        - "Family in the Old Testament" (2 Tapes ), n.d. (Box 83)
        - "Toward a Theology of Aging: Biblical Perspectives" / co-speaker Abraham Malherbe (Tape filed under Malherbe) (Box 81)
    - Panels/ Conferences/ Discussions
      - Black Seminary Conference
        - Cone, James: "Black Ecumenism and the Liberation Struggle" (Tape), 1978 (Box 86)
        - Lincoln, Eric: "The Social Cosmos of Black Ecumenism" (Tape), 1978 (Box 86)
        - Morse, The Rt. Rev. S. S.: "Who Else But Us?" (Tape), 1978 (Box 86)
      - Visiting Lecturers and Miscellaneous Recordings
        - Fosdick, Harry Emerson: "Living Under Tension" (CD/Audio Reel); "Modern Man's Rediscovery of Sin" (CD/Audio Reel), 1940 Jul 28 (Box 94)
        - Fosdick: "God Talks to a Dictator" (CD/Audio Reel), 1940 Oct 13 (Box 94)
        - Fosdick: "The Inescapable Judgement "(CD/Audio Reel), 1940 Dec 1 (Box 94)
        - Fosdick: "Decisive Babies of the World" (CD/Audio Reel), 1940 Dec 22 (Box 94)
        - Fosdick: "How to Stand Up and Take It" (CD/Audio Reel), 1940 Dec 29 (Box 94)
        - Fosdick: "When Great Events Make Common Tasks Seem Trivial" (CD/Audio Reel), 1941 Mar 23 (Box 94)
        - Fosdick: "What is Our Religion Doing to Our Character?" (Audio Reel), 1941 May 25 (Box 95)
        - Fosdick: "Getting Out of Us the Best That's In Us" (Audio Reel), 1941 Jun 1 (Box 95)
        - Fosdick: "Making the Best of a Bad Mess" (CD/Audio Reel), 1941 Jul 13 (Box 94)
        - Fosdick: "Christian Faith - Fantasy or Truth?" (CD/Audio Reel), 1941 Jul 27 (Box 94)
        - Fosdick: "Civilization needs a Soul" (CD/Audio Reel), 1941 Aug 11 (Box 94)
        - Weatherhead, Rev. L: "Conducting Worship" (Audio Reel), 1949 Apr 27 (Box 95)
        - Weatherhead: "In Divine Love" (Audio Reel), 1949 Apr 28 (Box 95)
        - Hanson, R: Lecture w/ R. McBride (Audio Reel), 1954 (Box 95)
        - McBride, R: Lecture with R. Hanson (Audio Reel filed under Hanson), 1954 (Box 95)
        - Hamilton, J.W.: "The Other Words of God" (Audio Reel), 1956 Mar 4 (Box 96)
        - Hamilton: "The Significance of His Silence" (Audio Reel), 1956 Mar 18 (Box 96)
        - Hamilton: "Power and Patience" (Audio Reel), 1956 Mar 25 (Box 96)
        - Hamilton: "The God of the Living" (Audio Reel), 1956 Apr 1 (Box 96)
        - Hamilton: "The God of Love" (Audio Reel), 1956 Apr 14 (Box 96)
        - Hamilton: "The God Who Speaks His Mind" (Audio Reel), 1956 Dec 9 (Box 96)
        - Hamilton: "The Contagion of Attractive Religion" (Audio Reel), 1958 Dec 14 (Box 96)
        - Hamilton: "The Best Things in the Worst Times" (Audio Reel), 1958 Nov 30 (Box 96)
        - H.B.A.: Kansas City Convention (Audio Reel), 1961 Oct (Box 96)
        - Day, Peter: Conference on the Christian Ministry (Audio Reel), 1965 (Box 96)
        - Corrigan, Bishop: Conference on the Christian Ministry (Audio Reel), 1965 (Box 96)
        - Hardy, Edward R. (Audio Reel), 1967 May 7 (Box 96)
        - Ebling, G: "Lecture" (Audio Reel), 1968 (Box 96)
        - Frei, Hans: "Current Developments in Theology" (Audio Reel), 1968 (Box 96)
        - Urbans, (Dean): Founders Day (Audio Reel), 1968 (Box 96)